I actually wrote a vim versus ide comparison
我写了一个 vim 和 ide 的比较
do you know how much faster vim was
你知道vim快多少吗
4.3 seconds 4.3 I saved every day
4.3 秒 我每天都省了4.3秒
all those months learning were
这几个月的学习
totally worth it
都是值得的
gq5 ⬆️ oh that's actually the model of
gq5 ⬆️ 那实际上是我的
my watch them or the eye whatever
手表或者眼睛模型
you either take the vim pill or
你要么吃下vim的安利
i won't talk to you
要么我不跟你说话
vim is the best editor i think. no? would agree
我认为vim是最好的编辑器 不同意？ 你会同意的
efficiency, do things faster
高效 干活更快
horrible, quick, everywhere, power, elite
恐怖 快 无处不在 力量 精英
powerful, ssh or how i like to call it
强大 ssh 或者我喜欢这样称呼它
make your life more efficient
让你的人生更有效率
10 finger typing
10 个手指打字
i have hobbies yes of course
我有爱好 当然有
i have a plan very fast everybody needs to learn
我有个计划 非常快 每个人都需要学习
vim yeah what what is school
vim 啥 啥是学校
what is school right we should learn vim
啥是学校 对吧 我们应该学vim
instead of school
而不是上学
right this is how i
对 这就是我
got you know what whatever
如何得道的 你懂的
you can go through the docs text manipulation
你可以进行文档文本操作
text manipulation continued
继续操作文本
social engineering oh that was the entire
社会工程学？  整个
alphabet is a command
字母表是一个命令
it just changes your life your productivity
它只是改变你的生活 你的生产力
it will be painful at first and painful at last
它在入门的时候会有点痛苦到最后还是很痛苦
good you need them to become a true software engineer
你需要它们才能成为真正的软件工程师
hacker no i don't use this term
黑客 不 我不用这个词
i just sit all day look at the window
我只是整天坐着看着窗口
yes it's fun yeah boys well what is fun
是的 这很有趣 孩子们 什么是有趣
right no evergreen skill
是的 常青技能
you don't really need a career once in a vim
你并不真的需要一个职业 一旦用了vim
vim is your career now
vim 就是你的职业了
what's the career anyway lightning speed shortcuts
到底是什么职业 闪电般的快捷键
no more mouse no more mice no more traps
不再有鼠标 不再有老鼠 不再有陷阱
hands stay on the keyboard light and portable
双手停留在键盘上 轻巧便携
vim is always there
vim 始终在那儿
no seriously you can't de-install it
说真的 你不可能在
without breaking your computer
不损坏电脑的情况下卸载它
no need to relearn ides if you get fired often
如果你经常被炒 就不用重学各种ide了
well it's actually i i don't have a gui on my computer
我的电脑没有gui
once you go vim you can never go back
一旦你用了vim 你就回不去了
you use it on remote servers anyway
在远程服务器上使用它
you might as well just
你也可以
use them all the time
一直使用它们
insert mode visual mode j o m k jk and suddenly you just
插入模式 可视模式 j o m k j k 突然间你就
become good at it
熟练用它了
let me give you a small command overview
我给你一本小小的命令概述
so vim you just need to learn it
所以 vim 你只需要学习它
it opens the door to wasting
它打开了在vim上浪费
more time in vim sure it might take one
更多时间的大门 肯定可能需要
year to learn the basics but it's worth it
一年来学习基础知识 但是它是值得的
if you ask me or anyone who uses vim
如果你问我或别人谁在用 vim
i'm not saying your ide is bad
我不是说你的 ide 很烂
but it's pretty bad you don't change vim
但是确实很烂 你改变不了vim
vim changes you if you're using a computer
但vim能改变你 如果你在用电脑
and you're not using vim that's pretty ridiculous
并且你没有在用 vim 这就很离谱了
vim is just a text editor
vim 只是一个文本编辑器
the shortcuts are a secret
快捷键是个秘密
good gotta do a bit more digging i don't recommend
好 再深入一点 我并不建议
anyone to vim i enforce it
任何人学习vim 我用代码
on them peacefully with code
以友善的方式强迫他们
between us i didn't really want to do this interview
说真的我其实不想做这个采访
it changes the way you look at it
它改变了你看待它的方式
and the way you look i gained 20 pounds
它也改变了你看的方式
i gained 20 pounds after i learned all the commands
我学会所有的命令后体重增加了20磅
and i lost 20 after i started using it
开始使用后体重减少了20磅
you're wasting time if you're not learning vim
如果你不学习 vim 你就是在浪费时间
you don't have to learn vim you must
你不是一定要学 vim 而是你必须要学vim
well vim actually feels quite natural to
使用Vim的人会
people who use vim first time i use vim
觉得Vim很自然 我第一次使用 vim
i was like whoa i can automate my ci no
我就像 哇哦 我可以自动化我的 ci
i'm like whoa i can automate my ci
and we don't need neural link we already have them
我们不需要神经链接 我们已经有了
them is like an extension of the human brain
它们就像人类大脑的延伸
you need to learn vim if
如果你使用电脑
you're using a computer
你需要学习vim
it's like using a car without a car
这就像你在用车却没有车
if you're using a computer you're kind of already using vim
如果你在用电脑 你已经在用vim了
and how's that? you will know then
它是啥？ 那时你就知道了
and it's not just for code you can use
不仅仅是在代码中
vim for many things
你可以用vim做很多事情
i use it for everything going to the grocery store
所有事情上我都用它 去杂货店
watching watches going to the watch store
看手表 去手表店
or whatever stores are out there
或者外面的各种店铺
haven't left the basement in a while
有一段时间没有离开地下室了
vim is so beyond
Vim是如此牛x
can you follow with the camera beyond
你能让相机跟着吗 牛x
vim bindings represent things i want to do in my head
vim在我的脑海中绑定代表我想做的事情
play pokemon
玩宝可梦
manually automatically once you start using vim
手动？ 自动！ 当你开始使用vim
it's like you acquired the ring in lord
就像你获得了《指环王》
of the rings
中的戒指
and you you get the analogy right
你明白这个比喻 对吧
you start changing files changing text files
开始更改文件 更改文本文件
changing system registry breaking your computer
更改系统注册表 弄挂你的电脑
repairing it nopes uh don't use vim
修复它 不 呃 别用vim
i don't even have a mouse
我甚至没有鼠标 你的
what you mean you don't have time to learn vim
你的意思是你没有时间去学习vim
and what do you have time for
你有时间去做什么
inefficient working inefficient work
低效的工作
inefficient lifestyle right whatever
低效的生活方式 还有别的
it opens the door for you doing other
它为你在命令行上做其他事情
things on the command line
打开了大门
extendable custom custom shell integration
可扩展 自定义 自定义 shell集成
grab grab grab a coding isn't just about
抓取 抓取 抓取 写代码不仅仅是
editing code it's about editing things
编辑代码 还包括编辑那些
that are not code system files readme
不是代码的东西 系统文件 自述文件
environment files notes mails commit messages
环境文件 注释 邮件 提交 消息
lots of things and vim can do
很多事情 vim 可以做
a lot of different things
很多不同的事情
you can watch everything in vim if you don't know how to
如果你不知道怎么做 你可以在vim中查看任何东西
vim can do all other ides can do
vim可以做其他ide能做的所有事情
plus plus more very powerful
加上再加上其他的 非常的强大
images videos binary files yes
图像 视频 二进制文件是的
let me give you an analogy here
让我在这里给你一个类比
you know what an analogy is right
你知道什么是正确的类比
same way car enthusiasts like to work on their own cars
同样的 汽车爱好者喜欢修理自己的汽车
programmers like editors that they
码农喜欢他们可以编程的
can program
编辑器
i'm not the only one that switches up gg
我不是唯一一个一直切换 gg
and shift g all the time right
和 G 的人 对吧
oh god i thought i've gone crazy
天呐 我以为我疯了
The actual interview
实际的采访